## Alex Vlasiuk

alex@vlasiuk.com

SUMMARY	
Math PhD with research and development experience in computational geometry and optimization.	
SKILLS	
<ul> <li>Programming: C, C++, Python, Matlab.</li> <li>Nonlinear smooth optimization, including multiple precision; BFGS, IPOpt, JAX.</li> <li>Data analysis: scikit-learn, pandas, OpenCV, R.</li> </ul>	
EXPERIENCE	
<ul> <li>PTC, Senior Software Engineer</li> <li>On the core geometry team for Creo – the PTC flagship CAD product. Development and maintenance of the geometry attachment functionality, its applications to engineering of composites.</li> <li>Design and implementation of an internal debugging and reporting platform. Recording and tracking of geometry creation for debugging and verification purposes.</li> </ul>	2023-
<ul> <li>Vanderbilt University, Senior Lecturer</li> <li>Conducted a numerical study of magnetic dipole interactions on planar lattices. Optimization using the IPOpt library and objective function evaluation with JAX.</li> <li>Advised two postdocs on a theoretical project modelling knots and links, and studying knot invariants by means of energy-like functionals.</li> </ul>	2022-5/2023
<ul> <li>Vanderbilt University, Postdoctoral Scholar</li> <li>Developed a multiple precision optimization package based on L-BFGS. Used it to approximate spherical codes with 20+ correct decimal places, allowing to recover their algebraic representations. Multiple precision implemented as a C++ template wrapper around the MPFR class.</li> <li>Won a joint Collaborate@ICERM travel grant, funding a meeting for a team of researchers.</li> </ul>	2021-8/2022
<ul> <li>Florida State University, Postdoctoral Scholar</li> <li>Developed Matlab packages for efficient point distribution in 3d with prescribed density. Both surface and volume distribution handled, up to 1M+ points.</li> <li>Advised two undergraduate research projects on collective dynamics and emergent behavior. Taught a graduate-level course on Lebesgue integration.</li> <li>Won an AMS-Simons travel grant.</li> </ul>	2018-8/2021
MATHEMATICAL	
Optimization over measures, computational geometry, point distributions, statistical mechanics.  2024 Alexanderson Award of the American Institute of Mathematics.  15+ publications and preprints in math journals, incl. Advances in Mathematics (in top 6 for pure math), SIAM Journal on Mathematical Analysis, Computers & Mathematics with Applications, etc.	
EDUCATION	
ICERM, Brown University, Resident graduate student researcher Vanderbilt University, Ph.D. in Mathematics Université de Toulon, Master I Mathématiques Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv, B.Sc.	2-4/2018 8/2018 5/2013 6/2013